# **Phoebe Badcock**

Northamptonshire phoebe.badcock@mail.com github.com/PhoebeBC phoebebc.github.io/Portfolio-Webpage/

Software developer, designing and building products to gain relevant experience, actively seeking opportunities to join the exciting tech sector and become a valuable team member. Over three years of experience at a finance start up.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

• SQL (Postgres Database)

Flask & APIs

Selenium & Webdriver

• GitHub & GitHub Pages

Jira & Confluence

Pycharm & VSCode

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Independent

January 2024–Present

- Storm Website (Full Stack Development): Creating a mobile web app for a local hockey club in-line with
  client requirements. Utilising MERN stack (Mongo DB, Express, React and Node.JS), I am mainly
  developing the backend aspect of the web app (Mongo, Express, Node) and collaborating with another
  developer for the react front end. This will provide an improvement in communication between organizers
  and participants, increasing the number of players and pushing up funding by 25%.
- Personal Portfolio (Web Development): Producing a website informing users of projects and experience.
   Advanced my HTML & CSS skills and improved my ability to research and adapt solutions.
- Computer Science Fundamentals: Seven days of intense learning with senior software engineer.
   Covered: Unit Testing, VMs setup and usage, Linux, Networking, Computer Architecture, Networks (TCP, UDP, TLS protocol), CIA Triad, Docker, AWS servers and Python, C programming Basics.

### STRATEGIC ANALYST (Promoted to Senior January 2023)

September 2020-January 2024

Snap Finance UK

- Building MI Dashboard: Constructed the base for new company wide analytics dashboard. Improved data
  refresh time form every hour to instantly upon page load. Used Flask APIs with a Python backend and
  embedded SQL queries to access data from the Postgres Database. With Jinja and Bootstrap supporting
  the frontend for interactive customizable diagrams, graphs and metrics.
- Process Optimisation: Improved the efficiency of testing decisioning changes. By implementing Selenium
  and Webdriver to push test applications through the QA environments, manual input became redundant.
  Time taken to test each change was reduced from six hours to one. Results were shared via Jira to the
  machine learning engineers to update or deploy the changes.
- Company-wide **Automation**: Collaborated and led a junior colleague to extend python automation scripts using API and SFTP calls. Over 10 process across five departments were improved, the greatest upgrade reduced a process from at least two hours to under 30 seconds.
- Customer Outcomes Review: Successfully completed FCA requested review of the five year history of the company. By constructing insightful data tables within the Postgres Database, £5 million saved in costs, and the FCA was fully satisfied with our customer outcomes.
- CRA Handling: Effectively oversaw credit reporting, including regular testing, checks and the sharing of the files to credit bureaus thereby fostering strong relationships through clear communication.

### **EDUCATION**

### **UNIVERSITY OF WARWICK**

October2017-July 2020

• Bachelor of Science in Mathematics: First Class with Honors

## TRENT COLLEGE

September 2010–July 2017

A Levels: A\*A\*AA Further Maths, Maths, Physics, Chemistry

GCSEs: 11 - A\*(6), A(5)